Finding Aid for the Ray Bolger Papers LSC.1117
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 17. Music, no dates, ca. 1920s-1980s; Boxes 50, 54-58, 60-65, 67-69, 70-72, 74, 79, 87-100, 102-103, 112, 129- 135
  - Commercial Sheet Music
    - I Got Plenty o' Nuttin', 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: George Gershwin Lyrics: Ira Gershwin, Du Bose Heyward
      From Porgy and Bess
    - I Hit a New High, 1937 (Box 130)
      Music: Jimmy McHugh Lyric: Harold Adamson
      From the motion picture Hitting a New High
    - I Like Ev'rybody, 1956 (Box 57)
      From: The Most Happy Fella Composer: Frank Loesser
    - I Like to Lead When I Dance, 1964 (Box 57)
      From the motion picture, Robin and the 7 Hoods Music: James Van Heusen Words: Sammy Cahn On cover: photographs of Frank Sinatra, Dean Martin, Sammy Davis, Jr., Bing Crosby, Peter Falk
    - I Love Me (I'm Wild About Myself), 1923 (Box 130)
      Music: Edwin J. Weber Words: Jack Holins, Will Mahoney
    - I Should Care, 1944 (Box 57)
      From the motion picture, Thrill of a Romance Composers: Sammy Cahn, Axel Stordahl, Paul Weston
    - I Still Love to Kiss You Goodnight, 1937 (Box 130)
      Music: Harold Spina Lyric: Walter Bullock
      From the motion picture, 52nd street
    - I Want a Girl (Just Like the Girl That Married Dear Old Dad), 1911 (Box 130)
      Music: Harry Von Tilzer (photograph on cover) Words: William Dillon
    - I Wish I Were in Love Again, 1937 (Box 57)
      From: Babes in Arms
    - I'll Bet You Tell That to All the Girls, 1936 (Box 130)
      Music: Sam H. Stept Words: Charlie Tobias
      On cover: photograph of Eddy Duchin
    - I'll Never Be the Same, 1932 (Box 57)
      Music: Matt Malneck, Frank Signorelli Lyric: Gus Kahn
    - I'll See You in My Dreams, 1924 (Box 57)
      Music: Isham Jones (photograph on cover) Words: Gus Kahn
    - I'll Smile Again, 1936 (Box 130)
      Composers: Dave Oppenheim, Michael H. Cleary, Max Rich
    - I'll Stand By, 1936 (Box 130)
      Composers: Benny Davis, J. Fred Coots
      On cover: photograph of Jackie Heller
    - I'm in the Mood For Love, 1935 (Box 57)
      Composers: Dorothy Fields, Jimmy McHugh
    - I've Got My Fingers Crossed, 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: Jimmy McHugh Lyric: Ted Koehler From the motion picture, The King of Burlesque
      On cover: photographs of Wawrner Baxter, Alice Faye, Jack Oacki, Arline Judge, Mona Barrie, Dixie Dunbar, Fats Waller, Nick Long, Jr., Kenny Baker, Gregory Ratoff
    - I've Got My Heart Set On You, 1937 (Box 130)
      From the motion picture, Ali Baba Goes to Town
    - Ida (Sweet as Apple Cider), 1920 (Box 57)
      Music: Eddie Munson Lyric: Eddie Leonard
      On cover: photographs of Benny Goodman, Eddie Leonard (the Minstrel) in blackface
    - If I Only Had a Brain, 1939 (Box 131)
    - If'n, 1956 (Box 57)
      Music: Harold Karr Words: Matt Dubey
      From: Happy Hunting. On cover: photograph of Ethel Merman
    - In a Little Gypsy Tea Room, 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: Joe Burke Lyric: Edgar Leslie
    - In a Shanty in Old Shanty Town, 1932 (Box 130)
      Composers: Joe Young, John Siras, Little Jack Litte
      On cover: photograph of Abe Lyman
    - In the Chapel in the Moonlight, 1936 (Box 130)
    - Is it True What They Say About Dixie, 1936 (Box 130)
      Composers: Irving Caesar, Sammy Lerner, Gerald Marks
    - Is This the Music of Love, 1931 (Box 130)
      Music: Ralph Rainger Words: Sam Coslow
    - It Seems to Be Spring, 1930 (Box 57)
      From: Let's Go Native. Music: Richard A. Whiting Lyric: George Marion, Jr.
    - It All Depends on You, 1926 (Box 130)
      Composers: B.G. De Sylva, Lew Brown, Ray Henderson
      On cover: photograph of Harold Ramsay
    - It's a Most Unusual Day, 1948 (Box 57)
      From the motion picture, A Date With Judy Music: Jimmy McHugh Lyric: Harold Adamson
    - It's Got to Be Love, 1936 (Box 57)
      From: On Your Toes Music: Richard Rodgers Words: Lorenz Hart
    - It's Love, 1953 (Box 57)
      Music: Leonard Bernstein Lyrics: Betty Comden, Adolph Green
      From the musical, Wonderful Town
    - It's So Peaceful in the Country, 1941 (Box 57)
      Composer: Alex Wilder On cover: photoraph of Peggy Lee
    - Jitterbug, 1939 (Box 131)
    - Jockey on the Carrousel, 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: Jerome Kern Words: Dorothy Fields
      From the motion picture, I Dream Too Much
      On cover: drawing of Lily Pons
    - Jones Boy, 1953 (Box 57, Box 130)
      Music: Vic Mizzy Words: Mann Curtis
      On cover: photograph of The Mills Brothers
    - Just One More Chance, 1931 (Box 130)
      Composers: Sam Coslow, Arthur Jonston
    - Land of the Long Ago, 1915 (Box 130)
      Music: Lilian Ray Words: Charles Knight
    - Last Night When We Were Young, 1936 (Box 130)
      Music: Harold Arlen Worlds: E.Y.Harburg
      Autographed by Arlen
    - Last Time I Saw Paris, 1940 (Box 130)
      Music: Jerome Kern Words: Oscar Hammerstein, 2nd
      Onc over: photograph of Kate Smith
    - Laugh Your Way Thru Life, 1937 (Box 130)
    - Let's Comb Beaches, 1942 (Box 130)
      Music: Johnny Green Words: George Marion Jr.
      From: Beat the Band
    - Let's Drift Away on Dreamers Bay, 1931 (Box 130)
      Composers: Harold Spina, George McConnell
    - Let's Put Out the Lights (and Go to Sleep), 1932 (Box 57)
      Composer: Herman Hupfeld On cover: Drawing of Rudy Vallee
    - Life, 1919 (Box 57)
      Composer: Pearl G. Curran
    - Life is a Song (Let's Sing it Together), 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: Fred E. Ahlert Lyric: Joe Young
      On cover: photograph of Frank Parker
    - Life is Just a Bowl of Cherries, 1931 (Box 131)
      Composers: Lew Brown, Ray Henderson
      From the stage production, George White's Scandals
    - Look For the Silver Lining, 1920 (Box 130)
      Music: Jerome Kern Words: Bud De Sylva
      From the motion picture, Sally
      On cover: photograph of Marilyn Miller
    - Love is Ev'Reywhere, 1936 (Box 130)
      Composers: Eddie Kusby, Case Kusby
      On cover: photograph of Hal Kemp
    - Love is Like a Cigarette, 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: Walter Kent Words: Richard Jerome
    - Love Like the Dawn Came Stealing, 1916 (Box 130)
      Composer: Charles Wakefield Cadman
    - Love Me To-Night, 1932 (Box 130)
      Music: Richard Rodgers Lyric: Lorenz Hart
      From the motion picture of the same title.
      On cover: photograph of Maurice Chevalier
    - Love Sends a Little Gift of Roses, 1919 (Box 130)
      Music: John Openshaw Words: Leslie Cooke
    - Love Songs of the Nile (Box 130)
    - Lovely Lazy Kind of Day, 1946 (Box 131)
      Music: Morgan Lewis Lyrics: Nancy Hamilton
      From the production, Three to Make Ready
    - Lover, Come Back to Me, 1928 (Box 57)
      Music: Sigmund Romberg Words: Oscar Hammerstein
      From: The New Moon
    - Lover of the Simple Things, 1963 (Box 57)
      Music: Mike Corda Lyric: Jack Wilson
    - Mad Dogs and Englishmen, 1931 (Box 57)
      Composer: Noel Coward From< The Third Little Show
    - Man Could Be a Wonderful Thing, 1947 (Box 130)
      Composers: Leo Corday, Leon Carr
      On cover: photograph of Hoagy Carmichael
    - Man Doesn't Know, 1955 (Box 57)
    - Manhattan, 1925 (Box 57)
      On cover: photographs of Tex and Jinx
    - Mahattan Serenade, 1928 (Box 57)
      Composer: Louis Alter
      From: Manhattan Suite
    - May the Years Be Kind to You (May You Always Walk in Sunshine), 1976 (Box 57)
      Music: John Edward White Lyrics: Atha-Lane Joyce, James Jay-Smith, John Edward White
    - Me For You (Wouldn't You Love It), 1929 (Box 57)
      From the musical comedy, Heads Up
    - Melody Farm, 1937 (Box 130)
      Music: Bronislaw Kaper, Walter Jurmann Lyric: Gus Kahn
      From the motion picture, Everybody Sing.
    - Melody From the Sky, 1936 (Box 130)
      Composers: Sidney D. Mitchell, Louis Alter
      From the motion picture, The Trail of the Lonesome Pine On cover: photograph of Sylvia Sidney, Fred MacMurray
    - Miss Mischeif, 1937 (Box 130)
      Composer: Ferde Grofe
    - Mr. Wonderful, 1956 (Box 57)
      Composers: Jerry Bock, Larry Holofcener, George Weiss
      From the musical comedy of the same title.
    - Mood I'm In, 1964 (Box 57)
      Music: Peter King, Lyric: Paul Francis Webster
      On cover: photograph of Jack Jones
    - Moon Madness, 1964 (Box 1957)
      From the musical Babes in the Wood Composer: Rick Besoyan
    - Moon of Manakoora, 1937 (Box 130)
      Music: Alfred Newman Lyric: Frank Loesser
      From the motion picture, Hurricane
      On cover: photograph of Dorothy Lamour, Jon Hall
    - Moon Over Miami, 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: Joe Burke Words: Edgar Leslie
      On cover: photograph of Ranny Weeks
    - Moonglow, 1934 (Box 57)
      Composers: Will Hudson, Eddie de Lange, Irving Mills
      From the motion picture, Picnic
    - Muchacha (Box 130)
    - Music Goes Round and Around, 1935 (Box 130)
      Music: Edward Farley, Michael Riley Lyrics: Red Hodgson
    - Muskrat Ramble, 1950 (Box 57)
      Music: Edward "Kid" Ory Words: Ray Gilbert
    - My Little Grass Shack in Kealakekua, 1934 (Box 130)
      Composers: Bill Cogswell, Tommy Harrison, Johnny Noble
    - O, Katharina, 1924 (Box 57)
      Music: Richard Fall Lyrics: L. Wolfe Gilbert
    - Oh! Look at Me, 1954 (Box 131)
      Music: Julian Slade Lyrics: Julian Slade, Dorothy Reynolds
      From the production, Salad Days
    - Ohio, 1953 (Box 57)
    - Old Soft Shoe, 1946 (Box 131)
    - On the Atchison, Topeka and the Santa Fe, 1945 (Box 131)
      Music: Harry Warren Lyric: Johnny Mercer
    - Once Every Year, 1971 (Box 57)
      Music adaptation: Mike Corda Lyrics: Paul Francis Webster
    - Once Upon a Nickel (Those Were the Good Old Days), 1951 (Box 57)
      Composers: Buddy Kaye, Tony Starr
    - One For My Baby, 1943 (Box 57)
      Music: Harold Arlen Lyric: Johnny Mercer
    - Over the Rainbow, 1939 (Box 131)
      From the motion picture, The Wizard of Oz.
    - Parlez Moi D'Amour = Speak to Me of Love, 1932 (Box 57)
      Composer: Jean Lenoir American version, Bruce Siever
      On cover: photograph of Lucienne Boyer
    - Pass That Peace Pipe, 1947 (Box 57)
      Composers: Roger Edens, Hugh Martin, Ralph Blane
      From the motion picture Good News
    - Put on a Happy Face, 1960 (Box 57)
      Music: Charles Strouse Words: Lee Adams
      From the motion picture Bye Bye Birdie
    - Puttin' on the Ritz, 1929 (Box 57)
      Composer: Irving Berlin
    - Quiet Girl, 1953 (Box 57)
      Music: Leonard Benrstein Words: Betty Comden, Adolph Green
      From the musical Wonderful Town
    - Raindrops Keep Fallin' On My Head, 1969 (Box 57)
      Music: Burt Bacharach Lyric: Hal David
      From the motion picture, Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid
      On cover: photograph of Paul Newman, Robert Redford, Katharine Ross
    - Rosalie, 1937 (Box 131)
      Composer: Cole Porter From the motion picture, Night and Day
    - She Touched Me, 1965 (Box 57)
      Music: Milton Schafer Lyrics: Ira Levin
      From the musical Drat! The Cat.
    - (I've Got a Woman, Crazy For Me) She's Funny That Way, 1926 (Box 57)
      Music: Neil Moret Words: Richard A. Whiting On cover: photograph of Eddie Magil, Megaphone King, Publix Theatres
    - Ship Without a Sail, 1929 (Box 57)
      From the motion picture, Heads Up On cover: photographs of Charles Rogers, Helen Kane
    - Shoe Shine Boy, 1936 (Box 57)
      From: Connie's Hot Chocolates of 1936
      Music: Saul Chaplin Words: Sammy Cahn
    - Shoeless Joe From Hannibal Mo., 1955 (Box 57)
    - Shoo-Shoo Baby, 1943 (Box 57)
      Composer: Phil Moore
      On cover: photographs of Joan Davis, Jane Frazee, Judy Clark
      From the motion picture, Beautiful But Broke
    - Slippy Sloppy Shoes, 1962 (Box 57)
      Music: Gerard Calvi Words: Harold Rome
    - Steam Is On the Beam, 1942 (Box 57)
      Music: Johnny Green Words George Marion Jr.
      From the musical Beat the Band
    - Straw Hat and a Cane, 1951 (Box 57)
      German words and music: Firtz Rotter, Heino Gaze English words: Roy Alfred
      On cover: photograph of Johnny Desmond
    - Swinging on a Star, 1944 (Box 57)
      From the motion picture, Going My Way Music: Jimmy Van Heusen Words: Johnny Burke
    - Taking a Chance on Love, 1940 (Box 57)
      Music: Vernon Duke Lyric: John Latouche, Ted Fetter
    - That's What a Rainy Day is For, 1953 (Box 57)
      Music: Vic Mizzy Lyrics: Mann Curtis From the motion picture, Easy To Love
    - That's Why Darkies Were Born, 1931 (Box 131)
      From George White's Scandals
    - There's a Small Hotel, 1936 (Box 57)
      Music: Richard Rodgers Lyrics: Lorenz Hart From the motion picture, Pal Joey On cover: photographs of Rita Hayworth, Frank Sinatra, Kim Novak
    - There's No Business Like Show Business, 1946 (Box 57)
    - This is the Mrs., 1931 (Box 131)
      Music and Lyrics: Lew Brown, Ray Henderson
      From the production, George White's Scandals
    - Three O'Clock in the Morning, 1922 (Box 57)
      Music: Julian Robledo Words: Dorothy Terris
    - Thrill Is Gone, 1931 (Box 131)
      Composers: Lew Brown, Ray Henderson From the production, George White's Scandals
    - Toy Shop Serenade (Box 57)
      Composers: Mike Corda, Joe Strom, Don Baker
    - Tu Volveras (Box 57)
      Composer: Agustin Lara
    - Twist, 1959 (Box 57)
      Composer: Hank Ballard Arranger: Alan Moorehouse
    - Two Lost Souls, 1955 (Box 57)
      From the Broadway production Damn Yankees Composers: Richard Adler, Jerry Ross
    - Very Soft Shoes (Box 57)
    - Walking Happy, 1966 (Box 57)
      Music: James Van Heusen Lyrics: Sammy Cahn
      From the musical of the same title.
    - We Saw the Sea, 1936 (Box 57)
    - We're Off to See the Wizard (The Wonderful Wizard of Oz), 1939 (Box 131)
      From the motion picture, The Wizard of Oz
    - We're Working Our Way Thru College, 1937 (Box 57)
      Music: Richard A. Whiting Lyric: Johnny Mercer
      From the motion picture Varsity Show
    - Whatever Happened to Ol' Jack, 1949 (Box 57)
      Music: Carl Sigman Lyric: Bob Russell
      On cover: photograph of Freddie Slack
    - Where Or When, 1937 (Box 57)
    - Who, 1925 (Box 131)
      Composer: Jerome Kern
      From the production, Sunny
    - With a Little Bit of Luck, 1956 (Box 57)
      Music: Frederick Loewe Words: Alan Jay Lerner
    - Would You Like a Strawberry Sundae (I'm Not Hungry), 1954 (Box 57)
      Music: Marian Deutsch Words: Margaet Deutsch, Elmer Chaput
    - Wrong Note Rag, 1953 (Box 57)
      From the musical comedy, Wonderful Town
    - Yankee Doodle Boy, 1931 (Box 57)
      Composer: George M. Cohan
      From Little Johnny Jones.
    - You Will Remember Vienna, 1930 (Box 57)
      Music: Sigmund Romberg Words: Oscar Hammerstein, 2nd
      From Viennese Nights
    - You're a Grand Old Flag, 1933 (Box 57)
      Composer: George M. Cohan.
      From George Washington, Jr.
- Series 18. Scrapbooks, no dates, ca. 1920s-1930s, 1965-1966, 1979, 1986; Boxes 41, 51-52, 70, 73, 109-110
  The Scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings docurmenting projects and performances from Bolgers early stage career. Additionally, there are scrapbooks from the IBM Golden Circle (1965 and 1979) and the University of Connecticut Honorary Degree ceremony. There is no specific arrangement to this series.
  - 1965 Golden Circle, 1966 (Box 52)
  - Black scrapbook of early vaudeville career, 1926-1928 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Blue Mill (The), ca. 1930s (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Blue scrapbook of early career, ca. 1931-1933 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    Mostly George White's Scandals clippings.
  - Green scrapbook of early career, ca. early 1930s (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Newman presents An Evening with Ray Bolger, 1965 (Box 52)
  - University of Connecticut honorary degree, 1986 (Box 52)
  - Wizard of Oz - photocopied scrapbook, no date (Box 70, Folder 1)
- Series 19. Writings By or About Bolger, no dates, ca. 1940s-1950s, 1970s-1980s; Boxes 20-21, 31-33, 36, 40-41, 48-49, 80, 131
  The series consists of printed and holographic writings by, about, an submitted to Bolger. Included are scripts, magazine articles, eulogies, and holographic notes. There is no specific arrangement to this series.
  - Atlantic City - script pages, no date, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    With screenplay synopsis for Beating the Odds.
  - Atlantic City - scripts, no date (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Atlantic City - scripts, no date (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Yellow script is a variation of the other Atlantic City scripts.
  - Biographical information, no date (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Cue Magazine article by Bolger, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Regarding Judy Garland.
  - Editorial by Bolger, no date (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Esquire Magazine article featuring Bolger, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Eulogies for others, no date (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - He Who Doesn't Get Hit by Margaret Lloyd, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Holograph notes, no date (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Folder of loose holograph pages found throughout the collection and collated to one folder. Appears to be generated by Ray or Gwen Bolger.
  - Holograph notes, no date (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Holograph notes, no date (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Holograph notes, no date (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Holographic notes, no date (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - Holographic notes about Judy Garland, no date (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Interviews with Bolger, 1950, 1974, 1979-1980, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Kathleen Carroll interview with Bolger, Hamilton, Haley, and LeRoy, 1975 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Love Boat (The) - story outline, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Marvelous Milton and the Red Carpet Limousine Service - series proposal and script, no date (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Profile of a Star: Ray Bolger by Hy Gardner, no date, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Scarecrow's Lost Dance Sequence article, 1985 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Strictly for 'Round' Actors by Bolger in Theatre Arts magazine, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Wizard of Oz (The) - book foreword, no date, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 12)
- Series 20. Publications, no dates, ca. 1930s-1980s; Boxes 112, 118, 135
  The series includes books, song books, and periodicals including Television Quarterly (14 issues) and The Dramatists Guild Quarterly (20 issues). Some of the books are signed to Bolger.
  - Assorted publications, 1936, 1965, 1970s (Box 113)
  - Books, no date, 1930s-1980s (Box 118)
    Songbooks, lyrics books, biographies. Some are signed to Ray Bolger by the author.
  - Dramatists Guild Quarterly (The) (20 issues), 1965, 1971, 1973-1978 (Box 112)
  - MGM's Marvelous Wizard of Oz and The Marvelous Land of Oz comic books, 1975, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Music publications, no date, 1939 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Television Quarterly (14 issues), 1973-1978 (Box 112)